<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kathleen McCulloch-Cop Blog</title>
        <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Kathleen McCulloch-Cop Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Curriculum Map - Grade 7 Mathematics]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/12/12/Grade7MathCurriculumMap</link>
            <guid>/2023/12/12/Grade7MathCurriculumMap</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Curriculum Map for Ontario Grade 7 Mathematics Curriculum]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The curriculum map created for the Ontario Grade 7 Mathematics Curriculum can be found <a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/CM_Math7-40801ef6ffef7f67271b69c703b387c2.pdf">here</a></p><p>A visual representation of this map is <a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/curriculummapcycles-bca0b27997c3034a4f6446b7a479a22f.pdf">here</a></p><p>The resources used to create this document are as follows:</p><ul><li><a href="https://buildingthinkingclassrooms.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Building Thinking Classrooms</em></a> by Peter Liljedahl</li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/5e43eabf-aede-47e7-8b0d-963f812f3166/Ele-Math-LRP_by%20QUESTION_G7-8_AODA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Long-Range Plan: Intermediate Division: Grades 7-8, Mathematics, Organized by Question</a></li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/f1c51925-304d-4f56-99ae-8d00cb3f115b/Ele-Math-LRP_by%20TOPIC_G7-8_AODA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Long-Range Plan: Intermediate Division: Grades 7-8, Mathematics, Organized by Topic</a></li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/9739e6ed-af75-4f1c-a8ca-b08b8c7d1f5d/Grade%207%20Course%20of%20Study%20-%20SCDSB%20%28AUG2020%29.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simcoe County District School Board Scope &amp; Sequence (Grade 7)</a></li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/fea57e07-4dd3-4720-b63e-ad749f45f4b7/Intermediate%202020%20DSBN%20Scope%20%26%20Sequence.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">District School Board of Niagara Mathematics Scope &amp; Sequence (Grade 7)</a></li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/d7fbcc68-2f2b-4ef8-988d-3fb9b42c33cd/high-impact-instruction-math.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">High-Impact Instructional Practices in Mathematics</a></li><li><a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/policyfunding/growsuccess.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Growing Success</a></li><li><a href="https://www.dcp.edu.gov.on.ca/en/curriculum/elementary-mathematics/grades/g7-math/strand-overviews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Grade 7 Math Strand Overviews Grade 1-8</a></li><li><a href="https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/fbd574c4-da36-0066-a0c5-849ffb2de96e/2e30175b-61ce-460b-86cb-9dad399496a2/Math_grades789%20alignment%20chart_AODA_06-May-21.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mathematics Grades 7-8-9 Alignment chart</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>lesson-plans</category>
            <category>math</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conceptual Framework - March 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/03/30/conceptualframeworkdraft</link>
            <guid>/2023/03/30/conceptualframeworkdraft</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Draft conceptual framework]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have had the privilege of never having to question my citizenship in Canada, and of not having it questioned. I’m white, born in an Ottawa hospital only 5 minutes from my childhood home. When asked where I was from, my answer was never met with “no, where are you actually from?” <!-- -->that I know follows the response of many people of colour who are also born and raised in Canada. And in parallel to that, I  have not had to grapple with the complexities of being Indigenous and Canadian and the ways that those two terms can seem at odds. Although I know of my privilege, and am actively trying to use it in solidarity with those who are not afforded the same, I’m still learning what it means to be Canadian. </p><p>While I have been trying to unlearn my biases and examine what constitutes the ‘glasses’ I wear (as Sensoy and Diangelo put it), I am realising that there is so much more that contributes to these than just the “big” ideas, such as race, class, gender, sexuality, religion, ability, and nationality. </p><p>My position as a teacher is not just as a white, cis, able-bodied woman—there are “smaller” factors (I do not say smaller to diminish them, just to distinguish them from the larger, easier to identify ones), such as my position as a 4th &amp; 5th Canadian citizen, that contribute to how I engage with my community. In my undergraduate degree, I studied how to conduct user-testing for systems — and part of that training included learning what my biases are, and learning how to enter a user-testing space without preconceptions of what a person may or may not know or be capable of based on what I perceive about them. I took this training with me, and knew that entering a classroom as a teacher, I would need to do the same, but while that was good, it was also a relatively shallow understanding of the myriad of factors that contribute to my privilege and my biases when interacting with others. </p><p>Clearly, there is no limit to the things that contribute to a person’s identity, as there is no limit on things that may happen in a person’s life, and so that work of unlearning bias and examining my preconceptions must be ongoing, as there is not an end goal. That would be impossible — what I can do is just always strive to be better, to be always more aware of what I think and believe and what that impact has on my view of the world.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>teaching-philosophy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NBE3U Unit Plan]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/03/21/NBE3Uunitplan</link>
            <guid>/2023/03/21/NBE3Uunitplan</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Unit plan for NBE3U course]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This unit plan was developed in February/March 2023, as part of the course <em>PED 4177 - Teaching English at the Senior Division</em>, by myself, William Peddle, and Kate Gray, using the template created by Linda Radford and Robert Ballantyne. </p><p>It was developed according to the most recent version of the curriculum <em><a href="https://www.dcp.edu.gov.on.ca/en/curriculum/secondary-first-nations-metis-and-inuit-studies/courses/nbe3u" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NBE3U - English: Understanding Contemporary First Nations, Métis, and Inuit Voices</a></em>.</p><p>The unit plan itself, <em>Positioning Story: Exploring Characterization, Thematics, Structure &amp; Style</em> can be viewed <a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/NBE3U_UnitPlan-b28b524cf9becf9901fac9fcc17589f3.pdf">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>NBE3U</category>
            <category>lesson-plans</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ENG4C Advertising Summative Task]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/03/03/AdsSummative</link>
            <guid>/2023/03/03/AdsSummative</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Summative task from 2022-2023 Practicum]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="overview">Overview<a class="hash-link" href="#overview" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The summative task for an advertising unit. Designed for a Grade 12 English College Preparation classroom. </p><p>The first two lessons for this unit may be found here: </p><ul><li><a href="/blog/2023/03/01/Ads1lessonplan">Lesson 1</a></li><li><a href="/blog/2023/03/02/Ads2lessonplan">Lesson 2</a></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="instructions">Instructions<a class="hash-link" href="#instructions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Welcome to the world of advertising! Madison Avenue is populated with high-rise buildings filled with advertising agencies, where everyday, people pitch advertising campaigns, sketch print advertisements, and write ‘copy’ (advertising scripts/slogans). You want to work there (doesn’t everyone?), but first, you have to pitch an ad campaign so the agency can get an idea of what you’ll bring to the table.</p><p>Don’t worry – the agency knows you’re working on your own, and that this is just a pitch. They only ask for <strong>between 3 - 5 advertisements (of at least 2 different formats) with a specific subject, audience, and message.</strong> Your audience and message need to make sense for the subject you choose.</p><p>Subjects can be one of :</p><ul><li>Product (something you can physically buy and own)</li><li>Service (non-physical things, for example insurance, healthcare, or tutoring)</li><li>Communication (an idea, message, or announcement)</li><li>Once you’ve made those decisions, you need to plan the details of your campaign. What <strong>ad formats</strong> make sense for your subject, audience, and message? What <strong>context</strong> makes sense for these ads?</li></ul><p>Finally, you will pitch your campaign – <strong>a 3 minute or less presentation where you tell us about your subject, audience, and message, your advertisements, and why the formats and contexts you chose suit them.</strong></p><p>Available formats:
| Format | 1 advertisment = |
|--|--|
| Tiktok video | 15 seconds of video |
| Instagram story post | 2 (different) image stories OR 1 (15 second) video story |
| Instagram posts | 2 (different) images AND associated captions |
| Print ad| 1 print|
| Radio spot | 15 seconds of speaking |
| Commercial | 15 seconds of video OR 20-frame storyboard|
| Billboard | 3 different billboard designs|
| Youtube/Podcast sponsored partnership |30 second script|</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="resources-and-documents">Resources and Documents<a class="hash-link" href="#resources-and-documents" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_AdsSummative_Slides-77c30e6c91b31f778bb77c3875b29248.pdf">Instruction slides</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_AdsSummative_InstructionsWorksheet-f59e1a3ee3c66a7710811c646ead44e1.pdf">Instructions and brainstorming document</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_AdsSummative_Rubric-ec4302892382aea9a13cd9db3ef05a63.pdf">Rubric</a></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="task-expectations">Task Expectations<a class="hash-link" href="#task-expectations" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Based on the <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/curriculum/secondary/english1112currb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2007 Ontario Curriculum for English Grades 11 &amp; 12</a></p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><em>Subject</em> ENG4C (Grade 12 English, College Preparation)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>Strand</strong> Media Studies, Oral Communication</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="ad-campaign-rubric-expectations">Ad Campaign Rubric Expectations<a class="hash-link" href="#ad-campaign-rubric-expectations" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Note:</strong> This task uses a variation on a <a href="https://www.cultofpedagogy.com/single-point-rubric/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">single-point rubric</a> which provides the criteria for students, and emphasizes feedback-centric assessment practices. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Expectation</th><th align="left">For this task it means</th><th align="left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Media Texts - Creating Media Texts</em></strong> <strong>3.1 Purpose and Audience:</strong> describe the topic, purpose, and audience for media texts they plan to create</td><td align="left">I can identify and explain the subject, audience, and message for my ad campaign.</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Media Texts - Creating Media Texts</em></strong> <strong>3.2 Form:</strong>  select a media form to suit the topic, purpose, and audience for a media text they plan to create, and explain why it is a highly appropriate choice</td><td align="left">The format of my advertisements are appropriate for my subject, audience, and message, and I can explain how the form relates to these.</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Media Texts - Creating Media Texts</em></strong> <strong>3.3 Conventions and Techniques:</strong> identify a variety of conventions and/or techniques appropriate to a media form they plan to use, and explain how these will help communicate a specific aspect of their intended meaning effectively</td><td align="left">I have used advertising conventions and techniques that are appropriate and effective for the advertisements I create, and the subject, audience, and message involved.</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Media Texts - Creating Media Texts</em></strong> <strong>3.4 Producing Media Texts:</strong> produce media texts, including increasingly complex texts, for a variety of purposes and audiences, using appropriate forms, conventions, and techniques</td><td align="left">I have created 3-5 ads, according to the guidelines in the instructions. They have a subject, audience, and message, and I have used conventions and techniques of advertising to accomplish the goal of my ad campaign.</td><td align="left"></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="presentation-rubric-expectations">Presentation Rubric Expectations<a class="hash-link" href="#presentation-rubric-expectations" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Expectation</th><th align="left">For this task it means</th><th align="left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Oral Communication - Speaking to Communicate</em></strong> <strong>2.1 Purpose:</strong> communicate orally for a range of purposes, using language appropriate for the intended audience</td><td align="left">I can present my ad campaign and clearly explain the advertisements I have created.</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong><em>Oral Communication - Speaking to Communicate</em></strong> <strong>2.1 Diction and Devices:</strong> use appropriate words, phrases, and terminology, and a variety of stylistic devices, to effectively communicate their meaning and engage their intended audience</td><td align="left">I can present my ad campaign using the vocabulary of advertising (e.g.: subject, audience, message, context, techniques.)</td><td align="left"></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>practicum-year1</category>
            <category>assessment-activities</category>
            <category>ENG4C</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ENG4C Advertising Part 2 Lesson Plan]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/03/02/Ads2lessonplan</link>
            <guid>/2023/03/02/Ads2lessonplan</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lesson plan from 2022-2023 Practicum]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="overview">Overview<a class="hash-link" href="#overview" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>The follow up to an intro lesson plan for an advertising unit -- going more in-depth with the components of an advertisement, and some of the ways that advertisements work. Designed for a Grade 12 English College Preparation classroom, within a 75 minute period.
Note: while this lesson is designed to be completed within one 75 minute period, it may be beneficial for students to have work periods between each lesson, in order to work on/complete the tasks and review the information, as well as to ensure that students are not overwhelmed with information or moving at a pace that is not conducive for full comprehension. </p><p>The first lesson plan in this unit can be found <a href="/blog/2023/03/01/Ads1lessonplan">here</a>. The summative task for this unit can be found <a href="/blog/2023/03/03/AdsSummative">here</a>.</p><p><strong>Guiding Question:</strong> <em>How do ads work?</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="curriculum-links">Curriculum Links<a class="hash-link" href="#curriculum-links" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Based on the <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/curriculum/secondary/english1112currb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2007 Ontario Curriculum for English Grades 11 &amp; 12</a></p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><em>Subject:</em> ENG4C (Grade 12 English, College Preparation)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>Strand:</strong> Media Studies</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Overall &amp; Specific Expectations</th><th align="left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>1. Understanding Media Texts</strong> <em>(Media Studies)</em></td><td align="left">demonstrate an understanding of a variety of media texts;</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.2</strong> Interpreting Messages</td><td align="left">interpret media texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts, identifying and explaining the overt and implied messages they convey</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.3</strong> Evaluating Texts</td><td align="left">evaluate how effectively information, ideas, themes, issues, and opinions are communicated in media texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts, and decide whether the texts achieve their intended purpose</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>2.Understanding Media Forms, Conventions, and Techniques</strong> <em>(Media Studies)</em></td><td align="left">identify some media forms and explain how the conventions and techniques associated with them are used to create meaning;</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>2.1</strong> Form</td><td align="left">identify general and specific characteristics of a variety of media forms and explain how they shape content and create meaning</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>2.2</strong> Conventions &amp; Techniques</td><td align="left">identify conventions and/or techniques used in a variety of media forms and explain how they convey meaning and influence their audience</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="work-skills--habits">Work Skills &amp; Habits<a class="hash-link" href="#work-skills--habits" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Addressed in this lesson are the skills of:</p><ul><li>Collaboration</li><li>Self-Regulation</li><li>Initiative</li><li>Organization</li></ul><p>As outlined in <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/policyfunding/growsuccess.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Growing Success</em> (2010)</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions--success-criteria">Learning Intentions &amp; Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions--success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions">Learning Intentions<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Today I will:</strong></p><ul><li>Practice identifying and understanding traditional and non-traditional advertisements </li><li>Identify &amp; understand the core techniques of advertisements</li><li>Identify &amp; understand the components of advertisements</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="success-criteria">Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>I can identify advertisements in a variety of forms</li><li>I can identify &amp; explain the subject/audience/message of an advertisement</li><li>I can  identify &amp; explain the technique a specific advertisement is using</li><li>I can  identify &amp; explain the components of a specific advertisement</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="lesson-execution">Lesson Execution<a class="hash-link" href="#lesson-execution" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="hook-review">Hook: Review<a class="hash-link" href="#hook-review" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>A hook focuses attention on the learning intention to come, provides a framework for the learning, and examples/analogies for understanding, and promotes interest and involvement and bridges from past lesson(s)/learning or prior knowledge.</p><p>In this lesson, students will very briefly review the core pieces of an advertisement, as they learned in part 1. </p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 5 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="development-techniques--components-concept-maps">Development: Techniques + Components, Concept Maps<a class="hash-link" href="#development-techniques--components-concept-maps" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The development provides experiences that guide and support students. Introduces content that is meaningful and relevant, challenges the students without frustrating them, actively engages the students, and involves a range of instructional approaches and activities. </p><p>In this lesson, students will  take a look at the core techniques advertisements (emotion, logic, credibility) and components of ad (context, form, design) and examples of how to identify these. </p><p>In small groups, students will then choose an advertisement from a given list, and create concept maps covering the subject, audience, message, techniques used, context, from, and design elements of the advertisements. </p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 45 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="closure-presentations">Closure: Presentations<a class="hash-link" href="#closure-presentations" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The closure is what the instructor does to facilitate wrap-up at the end of the lesson - it is a quick review, to remind students what it was that they have learned (or should have learned) and allows you to see where the students are to assist you in planning for the next lesson. May also help students to think about their own learning (metacognition).</p><p>Before the end of the lesson, students will, in their groups, present their  chosen advertisements and the concept maps they created to the class.</p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 25 minutes</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="assessment-strategies">Assessment Strategies<a class="hash-link" href="#assessment-strategies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Assessment FOR Learning: the teacher will collect and review the concept maps in order to see where students are at, what they know, and what they need more time on. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="documents--resources">Documents &amp; Resources<a class="hash-link" href="#documents--resources" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_Ads2LP_Slides-352c6c5e75fa990701149b51fccbfa33.pdf">Lesson Slides</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_Ads2LP_ConceptMaps-fc1fe319f5c5ddf2951584a078931a90.pdf">Concept Map Instructions</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>practicum-year1</category>
            <category>lesson-plans</category>
            <category>ENG4C</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ENG4C Advertising Part 1 Lesson Plan]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/03/01/Ads1lessonplan</link>
            <guid>/2023/03/01/Ads1lessonplan</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lesson plan from 2022-2023 Practicum]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="overview">Overview<a class="hash-link" href="#overview" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>An intro lesson plan for an advertising unit -- broaching what is an advertisement, how to identify ads, and the components of advertisements. Designed for a Grade 12 English College Preparation classroom, within a 75 minute period.
Note: while this lesson is designed to be completed within one 75 minute period, it may be beneficial for students to have work periods between each lesson, in order to work on/complete the tasks and review the information, as well as to ensure that students are not overwhelmed with information or moving at a pace that is not conducive for full comprehension. </p><p>The second lesson plan in this unit can be found <a href="/blog/2023/03/02/Ads2lessonplan">here</a>. The summative task for this unit can be found <a href="/blog/2023/03/03/AdsSummative">here</a>.</p><p><strong>Guiding Question:</strong> <em>What is an advertisement?</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="curriculum-links">Curriculum Links<a class="hash-link" href="#curriculum-links" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Based on the <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/curriculum/secondary/english1112currb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2007 Ontario Curriculum for English Grades 11 &amp; 12</a></p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><em>Subject:</em> ENG4C (Grade 12 English, College Preparation)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>Strand:</strong> Media Studies</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Overall &amp; Specific Expectations</th><th align="left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>1. Understanding Media Texts</strong> <em>(Media Studies)</em></td><td align="left">demonstrate an understanding of a variety of media texts;</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.1</strong> Purpose and Audience</td><td align="left">explain how media texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts, are created to suit particular purposes and audiences</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.2</strong> Interpreting Messages</td><td align="left">interpret media texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts, identifying and explaining the overt and implied messages they convey</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.3</strong> Evaluating Texts</td><td align="left">evaluate how effectively information, ideas, themes, issues, and opinions are communicated in media texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts, and decide whether the texts achieve their intended purpose</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="work-skills--habits">Work Skills &amp; Habits<a class="hash-link" href="#work-skills--habits" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Addressed in this lesson are the skills of:</p><ul><li>Collaboration</li><li>Self-Regulation</li><li>Initiative</li><li>Organization</li></ul><p>As outlined in <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/policyfunding/growsuccess.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Growing Success</em> (2010)</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions--success-criteria">Learning Intentions &amp; Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions--success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions">Learning Intentions<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Today I will:</strong></p><ul><li>Practice identifying and understanding traditional and non-traditional advertisements </li><li>Explain the subject, audience, and message in an advertisement </li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="success-criteria">Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>I can identify advertisements in a variety of forms</li><li>I can identify &amp; explain the subject of an advertisement</li><li>I can  identify &amp; explain the intended audience of an advertisement</li><li>I can  identify &amp; explain the intended message of an advertisement</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="lesson-execution">Lesson Execution<a class="hash-link" href="#lesson-execution" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="hook-is-it-an-ad">Hook: Is it an ad?<a class="hash-link" href="#hook-is-it-an-ad" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>A hook focuses attention on the learning intention to come, provides a framework for the learning, and examples/analogies for understanding, and promotes interest and involvement and bridges from past lesson(s)/learning or prior knowledge.</p><p>In this lesson, students will, as a class, rapidly cycle through a series of advertisements – ranging from classic, standard advertisements (ex: magazine prints, radio ads), to more contemporary and modern advertisements (ex: Instagram posts, sponsorship copy for podcasts). They will have approx. 5 seconds to decide if each one is an advertisement – and why or why not. </p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 5 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="development-review--scavenger-hunt">Development: Review &amp; Scavenger Hunt<a class="hash-link" href="#development-review--scavenger-hunt" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The development provides experiences that guide and support students. Introduces content that is meaningful and relevant, challenges the students without frustrating them, actively engages the students, and involves a range of instructional approaches and activities. </p><p>In this lesson, students will take a look at many different advertisements, and review the fundamental pieces of an advertisement (subject, audience, message). They will look back through the ones from the hook, and discuss what the subject/audience/message was, with guidance from the teacher. They will then, in small groups, practise identifying these elements for several new advertisements. Each group will share their findings to the class as a whole. </p><p>In their groups, students will then take on a scavenger hunt style activity. They will use tech to search for and find all the various types of advertisements as given to them in a scavenger-hunt-style list. They will need to identify the subject/audience/message for each of the ads found.</p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 55 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="closure-exit-card">Closure: Exit Card<a class="hash-link" href="#closure-exit-card" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The closure is what the instructor does to facilitate wrap-up at the end of the lesson - it is a quick review, to remind students what it was that they have learned (or should have learned) and allows you to see where the students are to assist you in planning for the next lesson. May also help students to think about their own learning (metacognition).</p><p>Before the end of the lesson, students will have some time to individually respond to a few questions:
What did they already know about advertising? What did they learn? What are they still wondering about? Which was their favourite ad they found in their scavenger hunt activity?</p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 15 minutes</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="assessment-strategies">Assessment Strategies<a class="hash-link" href="#assessment-strategies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Assessment FOR Learning: the teacher will collect and review both the practice worksheet and the scavenger hunt lists in order to see where students are at, what they know, and what they need more time on. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="documents--resources">Documents &amp; Resources<a class="hash-link" href="#documents--resources" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_Ads1LP_Slides-255342c171e3894b467d997858e7e560.pdf">Lesson Slides</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_Ads1LP_SAMWorksheet-cb0c3f6de6d6fb2f3420546265ba67b8.pdf">Subject/Audience/Message Practice Worksheet</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_Ads1LP_ScavengerHunt-8c584eb78d3e50a737ba8d945d1f49d0.pdf">Scavenger Hunt List</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>practicum-year1</category>
            <category>lesson-plans</category>
            <category>ENG4C</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ENG4C Active Reading for Research Lesson Plan ]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/researchlessonplan</link>
            <guid>/2023/02/28/researchlessonplan</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lesson plan from 2022-2023 Practicum]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="overview">Overview<a class="hash-link" href="#overview" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>A lesson plan for students to explore how to find sources within non-fiction texts which can guide them as they do further research on the topic at hand. Designed for a Grade 12 English College Preparation classroom, within a 75 minute period. </p><p><strong>Guiding Question:</strong> <em>How do we know where to find more information?</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="curriculum-links">Curriculum Links<a class="hash-link" href="#curriculum-links" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Based on the <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/curriculum/secondary/english1112currb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2007 Ontario Curriculum for English Grades 11 &amp; 12</a></p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><em>Subject:</em> ENG4C (Grade 12 English, College Preparation)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>Strand:</strong> Reading &amp; Literature Studies / Writing</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Overall &amp; Specific Expectations</th><th align="left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><strong>1. Reading for Meaning</strong> <em>(Reading &amp; Literature Studies)</em></td><td align="left">read and demonstrate an understanding of a variety of informational, literary, and graphic texts, using a range of strategies to construct meaning;</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.2</strong> Using Reading Comprehension Strategies</td><td align="left">select and use the most appropriate reading comprehension strategies to understand texts, including increasingly complex or difficult texts</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.3</strong> Demonstrating Understanding of Content</td><td align="left">identify the most important ideas and supporting details in texts, including increasingly complex or difficult text</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.6</strong> Analysing Texts</td><td align="left">analyse texts in terms of the information, ideas, issues, and themes they explore, examining how various aspects of the texts contribute to the presentation or development of these elements</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1. Developing and Organizing Content</strong> <em>(Writing)</em></td><td align="left">generate, gather, and organize ideas and information to write for an intended purpose and audience;</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.3</strong> Research <em>(Developing and Organizing Content)</em></td><td align="left">locate and select information to effectively support ideas for writing, using a variety of strategies and print, electronic, and other resources, as appropriate</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><strong>1.4</strong> Organizing Ideas <em>(Developing and Organizing Content)</em></td><td align="left">identify, sort, and order main ideas and supporting details for writing tasks, using a variety of strategies and selecting the organizational pattern best suited to the content and the purpose for writing</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="work-skills--habits">Work Skills &amp; Habits<a class="hash-link" href="#work-skills--habits" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Addressed in this lesson are the skills of:</p><ul><li>Organization</li><li>Collaboration</li><li>Independent Work</li><li>Self-Regulation</li></ul><p>As outlined in <a href="https://www.edu.gov.on.ca/eng/policyfunding/growsuccess.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Growing Success</em> (2010)</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions--success-criteria">Learning Intentions &amp; Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions--success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="learning-intentions">Learning Intentions<a class="hash-link" href="#learning-intentions" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Today I will:</strong></p><ul><li>Understand how external sources are presented in nonfiction texts</li><li>Practice identifying and finding citations, attributions, and/or bibliographies in nonfiction texts</li><li>Annotate non-fiction texts</li><li>Find external sources in nonfiction texts</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="success-criteria">Success Criteria<a class="hash-link" href="#success-criteria" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>I can identify an external source in a nonfiction text</li><li>I can annotate a nonfiction text</li><li>I can analyse a nonfiction text</li><li>I can compile a list of sources from a nonfiction text</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="lesson-execution">Lesson Execution<a class="hash-link" href="#lesson-execution" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="hook-wiki-rabbit-hole">Hook: Wiki Rabbit Hole<a class="hash-link" href="#hook-wiki-rabbit-hole" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>A hook focuses attention on the learning intention to come, provides a framework for the learning, and examples/analogies for understanding, and promotes interest and involvement and bridges from past lesson(s)/learning or prior knowledge.</p><p>In this lesson, students will start on the Wikipedia page for their high school. They will then have 2 minutes to follow the in-text links on the page, and see how far they can get from the original topic as possible. They will then share with the class what topic they ended on, and the path they took to get there.
<strong>Timing:</strong> 10 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="development-review--practice">Development: Review &amp; Practice<a class="hash-link" href="#development-review--practice" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The development provides experiences that guide and support students. Introduces content that is meaningful and relevant, challenges the students without frustrating them, actively engages the students, and involves a range of instructional approaches and activities. </p><p>In this lesson, students will review how information is cited/sourced in nonfiction texts, and how that can help with further research for a given topic. In small groups, they will practice finding external sources in a short sample non-fiction text (that they have seen &amp; read in a prior class), and how to determine which of those sources are most relevant to the research they would need to do. The class will then take up what they found. </p><p>Students will then choose from one of 3 articles provided, and complete a graphic organizer which contains 3 sections: </p><ul><li>What they know and are wondering about the topic before reading</li><li>A copy of the article as they have annotated it as they read</li><li>What they are still wondering about, what they learned, and where they can go for more information on the topic.</li></ul><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 45 minutes</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="closure-peer-sharing">Closure: Peer-Sharing<a class="hash-link" href="#closure-peer-sharing" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The closure is what the instructor does to facilitate wrap-up at the end of the lesson - it is a quick review, to remind students what it was that they have learned (or should have learned) and allows you to see where the students are to assist you in planning for the next lesson. May also help students to think about their own learning (metacognition).</p><p>In this lesson, students will gather in small groups based on which article they chose, and share what they filled out in the third section of the graphic organizer. Students will then hand in the graphic organizer. </p><p><strong>Timing:</strong> 20 minutes</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="assessment-strategies">Assessment Strategies<a class="hash-link" href="#assessment-strategies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Assessment AS Learning: students will share and review each other's ability to find relevant external sources within non-fiction texts.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="documents--resources">Documents &amp; Resources<a class="hash-link" href="#documents--resources" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_ResearchLP_Slides-40c03908c8de048f0ca970f562834307.pdf">Lesson Slides</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_ResearchLP_Organizer-33348b81889a641027274f5c889ba5cc.pdf">Graphic Organizer</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_ResearchLP_Article1-4f6c791be7770235342dfb295a3c5969.pdf">Sample Article 1 (<em>If Ticketmaster Botches Beyonce 'Renaissance'...</em>)</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_ResearchLP_Article2-436be1856590c1b587bc6f7cc1010593.pdf">Sample Article 2 (<em>On the Money</em>)</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="/assets/files/ENG4C_ResearchLP_Article3-a549e3fc61961df4ba668d01efa5ec6e.pdf">Sample Article 3 (<em>The NotSo-Social Network</em>)</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>practicum-year1</category>
            <category>lesson-plans</category>
            <category>ENG4C</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflections on Teaching Senior English]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/seniorenglishreflection</link>
            <guid>/2023/02/28/seniorenglishreflection</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Draft conceptual framework]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The act of teaching historically and traditionally, in Western settings, is synonymous with sharing expertise, with being a keeper of knowledge and therefore always the speaker, never asking questions without knowing the answer. As we move into inclusive and culturally-responsive pedagogy, that idea is being dismantled, and the <!-- -->position of a teacher as a person who makes mistakes, who is not the authority on any subject, let alone the one they are teaching, is being constructed. As is posited in ‘Read, Listen, Tell’, “We do not read from a so-called neutral, omniscient perspective from which we can under- stand everything” (pg 4), and neither do we teach — I cannot, as a white woman living on unneeded territory, pretend that I may ever teach any subject, particularly one such as FNMI Studies, without the lens of living and working as a colonizer, with all the privileges that I am afforded with that position. What I can do is be aware of my own positionality, and ask those questions that “Read, Listen, Tell” offers: “Who am I, how have my experiences shaped what I know, and what do I need to learn?” (Pg 4). Of course, the answers to those questions are not and cannot be static: my personal context, as it relates to my position as a teacher, will not be the same between any two texts. If I were to assume this, I would be at risk of narrowing what I may learn. To singularly and completely define any one thing is to exclude the potential that it holds and to reduce the capabilities it has; this is an idea that is repeated in “Read, Listen, Tell” and “Why Indigenous Literature Matters”: McCall et. all refuse to offer “a stable definition of what Indigenous literatures “are,”” as this would offer “definitions that risk excluding and silencing voices”  (pg 3), while Justice, again and again, asks us to expand our definitions as we approach what Indigenous literature is. While recognizing that no one definition may encompass all facets of the thing it tries to define—and more often than not, limits and excludes key pieces—is an important idea to keep in mind in all aspects of teaching, it is particularly critical when approaching Indigenous literatures and ways of knowledge. Justice remarks: “not all things are meant for all people”. I am not meant to understand the breadth of Indigenous cultures, I do not have the right to all of the knowledge and stories that an Indigenous elder may hold.  I can learn as much as I am able, and part of that includes learning that there are some things that I am not entitled to, that I may wonder at. I cannot ever be the foremost expert, nor should I expect to be.</p><p>As I navigate through Indigenous literatures, and the ways that knowledge is kept or shared depending on the positionality of the keeper and the reader, I reflect on how story changes too. Questions come to mind, such as: What do we know to be true? What stories have we been told and regarded as fiction, rather than truth? How do we navigate the past, our history (as people, as a country, as colonizers) while trying to balance those binaries of fact and fiction, history and story? While reading The Marrow Thieves, the ground is shifting constantly for the characters: they have built their understanding of the world based on the (hi)story they know to be ‘true’, but that story is told in pieces or winds itself around the facts, burying truth in fiction. When new details come to light, the ground shifts again, and we (along with the characters) have to reckon with and adapt to the new light that has been shed on the world they thought they knew. Whether those details are small, intimate truths, major events, or new chapters of stories we thought we knew, they change what we know to be fact, and what we know to be fiction, drawing new lines all the time. This is reflected in our world too: what I thought I knew about residential schools, and considered to be a full and true history, changed upon the discovery of mass graves in the summer of 2021. I find myself tracking mirrors of these changes, and mirrors of their reactions, in my own life. This text is allowing me a point of inquiry into how we see truth, how we understand fiction, and how history and story both inform our view of the world, and how that view changes with every new detail and every new story we are presented with. </p><p>Throughout, there are major themes of shifting perspectives. I am grappling with the understanding that what is in these works of fiction very closely mirrors our history as a country founded on colonialism and genocide. The binaries I am inspecting are not as dichotomous as we’d like to imagine they are: fact is often woven into fiction, and fiction can be presented as fact; but the question then remains, how do we engage with this text (with any text really) when we know for some, it will be truth, and for others, it will simply be a story?</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>teaching-philosophy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learning Blog - Reaching All Students]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2022/12/03/reachingallstudents</link>
            <guid>/2022/12/03/reachingallstudents</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[learning blog post]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an ideal world, all students would have the necessary skills and perform at the standards for their level. English teachers would be able to select one method of instruction, trusting that they would reach every student, and enable them to engage with the tasks and perform their learning. However, this is not the case. Every student has a unique set of skills <!-- -->performed at varying levels, and they will not all be engaged with or even capable of the tasks set before them. This presents a challenge for all subjects, but particularly in English classrooms, where conversation and discussion are large parts of fostering the critical thinking skills necessary for developing text analysis abilities, and connecting ideas and responding to others is critical for fostering reading comprehension skills. Some level of commonality is required for students to be able to work together, respond to each other’s ideas, and reflect on different perspectives of the same situation. Because of this, creating individual tasks or assigning different content to each student can lead to stagnation in learning, but generalised and uniform instruction will only reach so many students, leaving the rest out of these important conversations and activities. </p><p>So how do we reach every student on their level, while practising differentiated instruction and still creating that common ground on which students can connect with each other’s work? There are a lot of tactics, and as difficult as it can be to put into practice in English classrooms, the subject also lends itself quite well to this problem. </p><p>Literature circles are not only fantastic opportunities for practising collaborative group work and involving many kinds of texts in the classroom. They also allow for many different tasks centred on common content while involving different skill areas and levels, so that students can do work they are capable of, and still relate and respond to their peers. More than that, it facilitates the ability to use many texts at once, so all students can work with a text that they will be able to comprehend, and others are not bored or intimidated by the content they work with. Each group works with a text tailored (as much as is reasonably possible) for their skills and interests, and can take on roles within their group that will engage their interests and provide them with a point of entry into the conversation with their other members. That common ground is still available to students – they are able to hear from their peers, connect those ideas the a text they are familiar with, and respond in turn. When linked text sets are used, and the whole class is working in different lit circles on texts that relate to each other, even more connections are possible. Students can find commonalities between texts, ideas, and questions, and have a basis for connection and idea-building, without the skill level demanded by the content standing in the way of larger discussions. They can also see how their ideas and perspectives relate to a larger collection of work, allowing them to develop even more connections to and from their text, and founding a greater base for them to draw understanding and build ideas from, and still be working at a level appropriate for them. </p><p>Thanks to the broad umbrella of content that falls under the discipline of English, the actual content that may be used can also facilitate reaching every student while still providing general lessons. Students may struggle with classic literature, and that’s just fine, because reading comprehension and text analysis is still present in YA novels, graphic novels, short stories, poetry, and even magazines. Other texts that aren’t prose, like articles, biographies, poetry, informational brochures, and instructional texts can similarly be delivered on a variety of levels and can cover any content area possible. Essay writing may not come naturally to most students – but written expression and idea communication can be done with creative fiction assignments, storyboarding activities, letter-writing, daily journaling, summarising tasks, and concept maps. Because language is used in almost every aspect of our lives, there is practically no limit on what constitutes content in an English classroom, meaning that ideas like convention, form, and style can be discussed across any number of texts, allowing for students to engage with content that suits them as people and as appropriate for their skill level as learners, while still being able to relate their work to their peers and draw on conversations and common concepts in order to further their understanding. </p><p>While differentiating instruction and content for students can be intimidating, and certainly requires a delicate balance, it is essential for ensuring that students are engaged and learning in every classroom. While an English classroom necessitate some form of common ground in order to develop essential skills, the subject is thankfully flexible enough to accommodate for this in a large number of ways, from delivery methods to content to tasks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>teaching-philosophy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learning Blog - Literacy as a Resource]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/2022/12/02/literacyasresource</link>
            <guid>/2022/12/02/literacyasresource</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[learning blog post]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Canadian schools, English and Language Arts are at the core of skill development in nearly every classroom. Math, science, history, technology, business, arts: all of these require foundations in vocabulary procurement, comprehension of instructions, and information processing. However, because so often English class is associated with reading fiction and essay writing, it becomes siloed <!-- -->in students’ minds. The Ontario Secondary School Literacy Test aims to measure “whether students are meeting the minimum standard for literacy across all subjects” but still focuses on reading texts and writing . The ways in which literacy is applied in every subject is considered to be implicit. Students, particularly those who struggle with reading and writing, are expected to make the connection between their literacy skills and their abilities in other disciplines on their own. Often, students shrug at English classes, ask why they need to know the information, complain about how they don’t like reading anyways, so who cares if they’re good at it? They don’t see how it impacts their ability to create a successful resume, communicate with colleagues or supervisors, or process information that is not prose. As educators, we tend to forget or deprioritize this fact, when it should be at the forefront of a successful English classroom.</p><p>What tends to add to the isolation of English as a discipline is its content. As English teachers, we are predisposed to love the written word: books and stories are interesting and engaging, something that we not only love to study, but love to study with others, sharing thoughts and opinions, discussing what was interesting or surprising, dissecting the ways the story was crafted. Not every student feels the same – in fact, many students very strongly disagree with that view. Books are boring, often dealing with old and outdated ideas or settings. Having to not only read, but talk about (or god forbid, write about) narrative texts is torturous and seems pointless. What relevance does it have to their lives? How is reading books going to prepare them for the real world past grade 12 when they don’t even read outside of school? Of course, students are always reading, as both our digital and physical lives are saturated in text and written language. But the act of reading is not associated with scrolling social media or messaging with friends, due in part to the way English has traditionally been taught. When students who have gone through classes with ‘silent reading time’ meaning they need to physically hold a book and follow a story in their head, there tends to be no other definition of reading. If that action is the sole definition of reading, and literacy skills are equated to ‘reading skills’, then what does literacy matter outside of the English classroom? How does it apply to their real lives?</p><p>When this is the way English is taught and discussed, that’s a fair question. But when English classes and teachers make explicit the connections between the real world and the skills students are learning, suddenly, students can see how important English class is. When we step outside of the canon and traditional narrative texts, and focus on unconventional content, we can show students just how essential literacy is. Resumes, instructional guides, summary texts, professional communication; these are all texts that do not fall under the traditional concept of English class content, but are essential in a workplace. Skills like media literacy, processing, paraphrasing, researching, drawing inferences, and making connections all require strong foundations in reading comprehension and written expression, and can be fostered in many ways that do not follow traditional English classroom methods. Drawing on real-world examples, applying activities to students’ everyday lives, and showing them just how many opportunities become available for them with the procurement of these skills demonstrates to them how an English classroom prepares them for excellence in all areas of their lives, and we need to take care to prioritise this fact.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>teaching-philosophy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome!]]></title>
            <link>https://kmccullochcop.github.io/blog/welcome-docusaurus-v2</link>
            <guid>welcome-docusaurus-v2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[First blog post.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to this blog! Stay tuned for more updates!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>